Hi I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
嗨我是来自www.LearnVisualStudio.NET的Bob Tabor
In this lesson I wanna begin talking about layout
这节课我要开始讲Layout（布局）
or rather the process of positioning visual controls and other elements on your application's user interface
也就是将各种视觉元素在软件UI中定位的过程
And there are several different XAML controls that exist for the purpose of layout
有许多XAML控件为布局而生
and we'll cover most of the popular ones in this series of lessons
我会在本系列教程里讲到那些用得比较多的
Now in the past, Layout was relatively simple
在Win10以前，布局非常简单
after all you were tipped only laying out in an application for a single form factor
因为你只需要为固定的窗体大小布局
a single device like a phone or desktop application
比如像手机或桌面端这样的独立硬件
However there are few new rankles in adduce to as we begin to build up applications
然而当我们把这套用于做（基于所运行设备的）自适应缩放布局时
that can adaptbaly re-size based on the device that we run our app on
就开始遇到困难了
And this is one of the new key features in App development on the Windows platform
这就是在Windows平台上开发App的一个新的重要特性
We'll start with the easiest stuff in this lesson
我们先从最简单的开始讲
Then we'll build up to the more challenging stuff in the following lessons
然后在后续课程中慢慢接触更有难度的东西
Now before we begin I wanna point out one thing
正式开讲之前我还想说一点
Regarding all XAML controls that are intended for the purpose of layout
因为XAML控件是为布局服务的
most controls have a content property
所以几乎所有控件都有一个Content Property(内容属性)
so your button control has a content property, for example
比如Button(按钮)控件就有一个内容属性
And the content property can only be set to an instance of another object
同时这个内容属性只能被设置为另一个对象的实例
So, in other words, I can put a TextBlock when we just copy and paste code here to what I've got
换句话说……呃我先复制粘贴一个TextBlock(文本块)到这
I can create... here... a button... with a TextBlcok property
我可以在这用文本块的属性创建一个按钮
then I also add an Image inside of that button control as well
然后我又加了一个Image(图像)控件在这个按钮控件里
So whenever I tempt to put more than one control inside the content property I get this air by handle over
但当我尝试把多于一个控件放进内容属性里时就会有这条提示：
It says "the property 'Content' can only be set once"
“内容属性只能被设置一次”
However layout controls are intended to host more than one control
然而布局控件本应容纳多个控件
So as a result, they don't have a content property
所以结果就是它们都没有内容属性
Instead they usually have a children property
它们一般由一个子属性来代替
that's of a special data type - a Collection data type that can hold XAML controls called UI Element Collection
这是一种能容纳XAML控件的特殊集合类，称为‘UI元素集合’
XAML... As we add new instances of controls inside of the definition of our layout control
当我们把新的XAML控件实例添加进布局控件定义时
we are actually calling the add method of our layout controls'
实际上是在调用布局控件的'添加'方法
UI Element Collections or rather just the collection property
它们属于UI元素集合或者说集合属性
So here again XAML has a lot of complexity for us
所以再强调一次，XAML有很多高明之处
and makes our code very concise by inferring your intent by how we write our XAML
这使得XAML可以根据代码风格推断我们的意图，从而使代码简洁明了
Alright, so we gonna begin in lesson looking at the Grid control
好了 那么我们从Grid(网格)控件开始这一课
like any Grid, it allows you to define both rows and columns to create itself
像所有的网格一样，你可以通过定义行和列来创建网格控件
and then each of the controls that are used by your application can request which row and which column that they wanna be placed inside of
你App里用到的每个控件都能指定自己被放在哪行哪列
So whenever you create a new app using the blank app template you are provided very little guidance
当你用初始模板创建新App时不会有多少引导
that you saw here a moment ago
就像你刚才看到的那样
Let me just get rid of that...
我先删掉这段...
That's pretty much all you are given to get started
一开始你只有这么点儿东西
You get a single empty Grid with no rows and no columns to find
只有一个找不到行列定义的空网格
However, by default, there's always one row definition and one column definition
但默认情况下 总有一个行定义和一个列定义
even if it's not implicitly defined in your XAML
即使没有在XAML中显式定义它们
And these take up the full vertical and horizontal space available to represent one large cell in the Grid
它们定义出的单元格占据了当前网格控件中的所有空间
Now any items that are placed between that opening and closing Grid element are understood be inside of that single implicitly defined cell
在"Grid"和"/Grid"之间的元素就被放置在这个隐式定义的单元格中
So I want to create a quick example of a Grid that defines two rows
我们来示范性地做个有两行的网格控件
just illustrate two primary ways of creating rows and setting there heights
来介绍两种创建行并设置其高度的方法
And so actually I've already taking the opportunity to create this
呃...实际上我早就做好了这个
Someone who go to the project called "Row definition" you should be able to open this up and follow along
你们可以到Row Definition项目下打开它然后跟着做
or you can just possibly type this in as well
或者粗暴点直接把这段代码打上去
So here you can see that I want you to notice how that I have two rectangles:
我希望你注意到这儿有两个矩形
there's a upper rectangle and a lower rectangle
上面有一个，下面有一个
And those are defined through series of row definition objects, here
它们是通过这儿的行定义对象来定义的
So you can see that I have inside of the Grid that has the property element syntax that define a collection of Row Definitions
在网格控件里有两个通过属性元素语法定义的行定义集合
with instances of Row Definition created with their height property set
同时有定义他们高度属性的行定义实例
And here the first one has its height property set to Auto
在这儿第一个的高度属性设置为'Auto'
and its second row definition object has its height set to Star
第二个行定义对象高度设置为'*'
And then we have two rectangle objects
这里有两个矩形对象
and notice that here we're setting the row that this rectangle object wants to put itself inside of
注意一下 我们在这儿设置矩形放在哪行
It wants to put inside... itself inside of the row 0, so we can see that this is the first row, row 0, so 0 based
它想被放到行0里 呐我们看最上面一行是行0
And then the second rectangle wants to put itself inside of the Grid row equals 1, so it puts itself here - in this row
然后第二个矩形想被放到行1里 就是这行
So the first thing we notice is how the rectangles are putting themselves into the various Grid rows
嗯我们看到如何把这俩矩形放置到不同的行中
And then also how you reference both rows and columns using a 0 based numbering skill that we saw here
和如何用以0为基底的计数制来使用行和列
And the second thing I want you notice is this wired syntax "Grid.Row"
第二个重点是这个奇怪的语法'Grid.Row'
"Grid.Row" will also be setting "Grid.Column" in another example here
'Grid.Row'也可以是'Grid.Column'
And these are called Attached Properties
我们称之为Attached Properties(附属属性)
And An Attached Property enable an object - in this case a rectangle - to assign the value for property
附属属性允许对象(本例中是矩形)通过指定属性的值
in this case the row property but it could apply to the column property as well
(这个例子中是行属性但是应用到列属性上是一样的)
to assign the value for property that its own class structure doesn't define
来指定它的本身类结构中没有定义的属性的值
So nowhere in the rectangle definition is there a Grid.Row property or even a row property
所以在矩形定义里没有Grid.Row属性或者行属性
These are all defined inside of the Grid object
这些都是在网格对象里被定义的
And the reason why Attached property exist
至于为什么附属属性存在嘛
is really an advanced XAML topic that's not ac-curable at this point in your introduction to XAMLs
我现在不打算在XAML入门教程里谈这种高难度问题
So I'm going to skip that topic
我准备跳过这个问题
if you want to get deeper into the internals of XAML
如果你想更深入地了解XAML核心机制
then you should search MSDN for articles about both Attached Properties as well as the loosely related topic of Dependency Properties
那就去MSDN搜‘Attached Properties’以及相关的'Dependency Properties'主题
but in a lot shells Attached Property keep your XAML simple
一般来说 附属属性可以让XAML更简单
Let's just leave it that and you can go off and explore that topic little bit a lot on your own later on
我们还是别管这个问题了 课后自己去浏览相关主题吧
So the third thing that I want you to notice about in this example are the two different row heights
我希望你在这个例子中注意的第三点是两种不同的行高
the first height we set 'Auto' and the second row height we set '*'
第一个高度我们设置为'Auto' 第二个设置为'*'
there are 3 syntax s that you can use to help per-sway the sizing for each row and each column
有三种语法可以用来确定行和列的大小
I use the term "per-sway" intentionally
我故意用了'Persuaing'这个词(爆伯这真的是个词吗词典都翻不到)
with XAML layout, heights and widths are relative
在XAML布局中，高和宽是相关联的
They can be influenced by a number of different factors
它们会被许多因素影响
All of these factors are considered by the layout engine and Runtime
布局引擎和运行库会综合考虑这些影响因素
to determine the actual placement of items on your given page or your screen
以确定元素在页面上的实际布局位置
So for example, this term "Auto" means that the height for the row should be tall enough to accommodate all the controls that are placed inside of that row
举个例子，'Auto'表示行高需要足够高以容纳放置在此行里的控件
If the tallest control... in this case you can see this rectangle as its height explicitly set to 100 pixels
如果最高的控件... 额这个例子里的矩形高被明确设定为100像素
If the tallest side is 100 pixels tall then that's the actual height of the row, 100 pixels
如果最高的边有100像素 那么这就是此行的实际高度 100像素
If we go change this to 50 pixels
如果我们把它改成50像素
you can see that the height of row changes now we have the height to 50 instead
可以看到行高变成了50像素
let's change it back to 100
我们还是把它改回100...
So therefore "Auto" means that the height is relative to the controls that are inside of that
所以'Auto'意思是高度与行内控件相关联
even row or column or whatever the case might be
对于行和列或者不管其他什么鬼来说都是一样的
Secondly you see this asterisk is also known as Star Sizing
第二种 这个'*'也叫做Star Sizing (用星号确定尺寸大小-简称'星号标尺')
It means that the height of the row should take up all of the rest of the available height available
意思是行高会占据所有空余可用的高度
So here's a quick example of another way to use Star sizing
来看个如何使用星号标尺的例子
I created a project that has 3 rows and in a content panels here we get to Star sizing
我在面板上新建了有三个行的项目 额...用了星号标尺
So again you can see that we have 3 rows that are defined... just down here... like so
可以看到 我们像这样定义了三个行
Notice that the heights of each one of them... Putting the number before the "*"
注意 在每个行高的'*'前都有数字
I'm saying of all the available space give me one share of all the available space
这行在说'给我一份空间'
or two shares of all the available space
这行说'给我两份空间'
or in this case three shares of all the available space
这行说'给我三份空间’
So the sum of all these rows adds up to 6
三行的加起来是六份
So each one star is equivalent to 1/6 of the height that's currently available
所以每个'*'等于1/6的当前可用高度
So therefore 3 stars would get half of the height that's available as a picked in the output of this example
因此在这个例子里'3*'就代表了一半的可用高度
You should see it gets... half of the available height
你看 一半的可用高度
I also want you to notice off to the left hand side
我希望你注意下左手边
that there are some visual tools that we can use to... to change the... the sizing
这儿有许多可视化工具用来改变控件尺寸
so for example I can change from stars sizing to Auto or to pixel
比如可以从星号标尺改成自动标尺或像素标尺
I can also just type in the given value here and that will set the height property in this particular case
还可以像这样在这儿直接输入确定值来设置高度属性
Besides Auto and Star sizing
除了自动标尺和星号标尺
you can also specify widths and heights as well as margins in terms of pixels
你还可以用Margin(余量)来按像素确定宽和高
So in fact, when only numbers are present
事实上 当只有数字的时候
it represents that number of pixels or the width or height
数字就代表了那么多像素的宽或者高
but generally it's not a good idea to use exact pixels in layouts for widths and heights
但一般来说在布局中使用固定像素确定宽和高并不合适
because it'll likely heard that various screens will be larger or smaller
因为在不同尺寸的屏幕上它会变大或变小
So there are several different types of phones or several different form factors for tablets and desktops...things of that nature
毕竟有许多不同型号的手机、平板和桌面端（对应着不同的窗体）
And so you don't want to specify exact numbers
因此不应该确定固定的数字
or else it's not gonna look correct on different form factors
不然布局在不同界面上就会看着不对劲
Instead, it's preferable to use relative layout like Auto and Star sizing for layout
因此 推荐你在布局时使用关联布局比如自动标尺和星号标尺
Now the one other thing that I want you to notice from this example is that
这个例子里还有另一点需要你注意
In XAML control, widths and heights are assumed to be 100%
在XAML控件中 宽和高假定为100%
unless otherwise specified, especially for rectangles
除非有别的明确定义（特别是对矩形而言）
That's pretty much true for many different controls
这对很多不同控件都成立
not all controls, like the button control doesn't treated this way
但也不是所有控件 比如按钮控件就不遵循这个规则
but the rectangle, the image control... These are all assumed to be 100% of whatever space that's available widths and heights
对于矩形和图形控件而言 它们会占据100%的可用宽高
I also want to point out that a Grid can have a collection of column definitions
还需要指出的一点是 网格可以拥有一个集合的列定义
And what I want to do...show you another example here
呃再给你看个例子...这里
And so there you can see that we have a 3 by 3 Grid, 3 row definitions
这里有个3×3的网格 3个行定义
and then we see there are also with property-only syntax defining a column definition's collection that contains 3 columns
然后这儿用属性限定语法来定义此包含三个列的列定义集合
Further more you can see that I put a TextBlock inside of each one of the cells
更进一步 我在每个单元格里放了个文本块
Now unfortunately you can't see the numbers here on the designer
可惜 没法从设计视图看到这些数字
It's not represented done correctly
它没有被正确显示出来
but if we were to run the application, you'll be able to see that we get different number in each cell
但如果我们运行这个App就能看到在不同单元格里有不同数字
Smaller, we see 1-9
缩小点 可以看到1-9
And one thing that I want you to notice for example
你还需要注意一点 举个例子
in this very first cell the upper left hand corners that I'm not setting a row nor am I setting a column
在第一个也就是左上角那个单元格里 我没有设置行和列
So by default if you don't supply that information it's assumed to be 0
默认情况下 如果你不提供行列信息 它就会是0
So we are assuming that we are putting this particular TextBlock in row 0, column 0
所以我们实际上假设了我们把这个文本块放在行0列0
Further more if you take a look at this next TextBlock and setting the Grid column equals 1
更进一步 把下一个文本块中设置网格列为1
but I'm not setting the row meaning that I'm assuming that be 0
但没有设置行 这意味着它为0
and I do that here several times throughout this example
我在这例子里做了很多遍这样的操作
So relying on the defaults keeps you code gain more precise
依靠默认值可以使代码更简洁
but you have to be understand there's a convention being used here
但必须了解的是 这里用了一个转换
Alright I have another example that I want to show you called Alignment & Margins
我还有个叫做'对齐&余量'的例子要给你看
let's bring this down...
拖下来一点...
Most of these examples should be pretty obvious to be stared at for a few moments
这些例子看上去应该很清晰明了
but there are several finer distinctions that I wanna make about alignments and margins
但关于对齐和余量 还有些更优秀的特性
First of all, this example illustrates how vertical alignment and horizontal alignment work even in a given Grid cell
首先 这个例子介绍了在给定网格单元格中垂直对齐和水平对齐如何发挥作用
And this is whole true in a stack panel as well we'll talk about in the next lesson
这对我们下节课将要讲到的StackPannel同样适用
The vertical or horizontal alignment property attributes pull controls towards their boundaries
垂直对齐和水平对齐将控件拉向其边界
So by contrast, the margin attributes push controls away from their boundaries
与之相反 余量将控件推离其边界
So in this case here, you can see that the horizontal alignment were pulling this blue rectangle towards the left hand side
因此这种情况下 可以看到水平对齐将蓝色矩形拉到左手边
and were pulling it towards the top hand side
同时把它拉向顶端
However if we take a look at the example that has some margins to find
仔细看这个关于余量例子
Here to very bottom, this white one
最下面 这个白色的
So here again, we are pulling the horizontal alignment towards the left
水平对齐将其拉向左边
and pulling the vertical alignment towards the bottom
同时垂直对齐将其拉向底端
And then we are setting the margins equal to "50,0,0,50"
然后我们设置余量为'50,0,0,50'
so you can see that the margin will now push the rectangle away from the left hand boundary by 50
可以看到余量现在把这个矩形推离左侧边界50像素
So you can see here that... we can that... spacing the left hand side
这样就可以为左侧留出空间
And the margin is pushing the white rectangle away from the bottom boundary by 50 pixels as well
余量同时也把白色矩形推离底端50像素
Now for second observation that I wanna make is the odd way which margins are defined
第二点要注意的是余量的不寻常定义方式
We already talked about this so we're not get horrible on this in this lesson
我们已经讲过了这个了 所以这节课不准备在这上面纠结
Margins are represented as a series of numeric values that are separated from... by commas
余量以一串逗号分隔的数字表示
and this convention was borrowed from cascaded style sheets
这种转换是从串联型表单借鉴来的
So the numbers represent the margin pixel values
数字代表了余量像素值
in a clockwise fashion starting at the left hand side
从左手边开始顺时针方式记录
So in this case left-top-right-bottom, alright
所以顺序是 左 上 右 下
A bit earlier I said that it's generally a better idea to use relative sizes like Auto or Star sizing whatever you want to find heights and widths
之前我说过在需要高度和宽度时用关联布局比如自动标尺和星号标尺比较好
So why is then that margins are defined in exact pixels ?
那么为什么余量却要用像素来定义呢？
Well, usually margins are just small values or white spacing or padding between two relative values
呃...通常呢 余量是极小的空白值或者两个相关联控件的间隙
And so they can be fixed without negatively impacting the overall layout of the page，you mean
因此它可以在不影响整体布局的情况下确定位置
If you want a small amount of space between two rectangles
如果你想在两个矩形中间留出小空隙
50 pixels will be enough whether you have a large or small size
对大小不一的尺寸来说50像素都够了
And if it's not you can change it through other techniques that will demonstrate later on in this series
如果还不行 你还可以借助本教程后期将介绍的其他手段做些改进
So let's recap what we've talked about so far
好 我们来回顾下到目前为止都讲了些什么
In this lesson we talked about layout controls
这节课我们讲了布局控件
and how they allow you to find areas of your application, where other visual XAML controls will be hosted
讲了它们如何在你的App中或者在其他可视化XAML控件间确定位置
In this lesson we specifically learned about the Grid and how to define columns and rows
这节课我们讲了网格控件和如何定义行列
how to define their relative sizes using Star or Auto
如何运用星号标尺和自动标尺定义它们的相对大小关系
And then how to specify which row and column are given control would request to be inside of
如何通过设置给定项目(这个例子中是矩形或者其他像它的项目)的附属属性
by setting attached properties "Grid.Row" or "Grid.Column" on that given item
如'Grid.Row'或者'Grid.Column'
or the rectangle in this particular case or whatever like it
来确定其应该被放置在哪行哪列
We also talked about how to set the alignment and the margins of those controls inside of the given cell and more
我们还讲了如何对给定空间内的控件设置对齐和余量
So Grids are great but they're really just one tool
网格控件很赞 但它只是一个工具
You can likely use them along with other layout controls like this StackPanel which we'll learn about in the very next lesson
你可以试着把它和其他布局控件比如我们下节课要学的堆栈布局合在一起用
So see you there, thank you.
那我们下期再见